<resources>
    <string name="app_name">IELTSPrepApp</string>

    <!-- MainActivity Strings -->
    <string name="tv_screen_text">Prepare for IELTS with our free practice tests and answers.
        Use these tests to carry out timed practice sessions and develop your test technique. </string>
    <string name="btn_listening">LISTENING</string>
    <string name="btn_reading">READING</string>
    <string name="btn_speaking">SPEAKING</string>
    <string name="btn_writing">WRITING</string>

    <!-- ListeningActivity Texts -->
    <string name="submit_button_text">SUBMIT</string>
    <string name="submit_button_text_submitted">SUBMITTED</string>
    <string name="custom_media_player_title_text">Title</string>
    <string name="custom_media_player_description_text">Press for listening:</string>
    <string name="custom_media_player_description_text_playing">State : Playing</string>
    <string name="custom_media_player_description_text_stopped">State : Stopped</string>
    <string name="custom_fill_blank_view_submit_blank_text">SUBMIT</string>

    <!-- ReadingActivity Texts -->
    <string name="reading_first_warning">READING PASSAGE 1\n
        You should spend about 20 minutes on Questions\n
        1–13, which are based on Reading Passage 1 below.</string>
    <string name="reading_first_title">EXTRACTION AND PURIFICATION OF DRINKING WATER</string>
    <string name="reading_first_paragraph_first">Some consumers choose to purchase bottled drinking water,
        rather than relying on city tap water supplies. Bottled water has typically been extracted
        from underground sources. If water exists underground, but has no natural exit points,
        bottling companies may construct a water table well by drilling down to extract water from
        an unconfined aquifer. This is done when the Earth’s natural water level-known as a water
        table – is much lower than the Earth’s surface. In some cases, as with a valley or gully on
        a mountain, the level of the water table may be higher than the Earth’s surface, and a
        natural spring can emerge. Bottling companies are permitted to extract this water from a
        hole drilled into the underground spring, but the composition of the water must be identical
        to that of the naturally surfacing variety nearby.</string>
    <string name="reading_first_paragraph_second">Artesian water is drawn from a confined aquifer,
        a deep underground cavity of porous rock that holds water and bears pressure from a
        confining layer above it. This water can be accessed if companies drill a vertical channel
        down into the confined aquifer. Due to the pressurised nature of this aquifer, water will
        often rise up from within it and form a flowing artesian well, which appears as an explosive
        fountain at the earth’s surface. However, this only occurs when the surface is lower than
        the natural water table. If the surface is not lower than the natural water table, it is
        still possible to draw artesian water by using an extraction pump.</string>
    <string name="reading_first_paragraph_third">Some bottled water is advertised as ‘purified’,
        which means it has been subjected to a variety of different cleansing processes. A common
        filtering procedure, known as reverse osmosis, involves the water being pressed through
        microscopic membranes that prevent larger contaminants from passing through. The microscopic
        size of these holes is such that they can even obstruct germs, but they are most effective
        against undesirable materials such as salt, nitrates and lime scale. One disadvantage of
        reverse osmosis is that a lot of unusable water is generated as a by-product of the
        procedure; this must be thrown away.</string>
    <string name="reading_first_paragraph_forth">For treating pathogens, an impressive newer option
        is ultraviolet (UV) light. Powerful UV light has natural antibacterial qualities, so this
        process simply requires water to be subjected to a sufficient strength of UV light as it
        passes through a treatment chamber. The light neutralises many harmful germs by removing their
        DNA, thereby impeding their ability to replicate. A particularly impressive quality of
        UV light is its ability to neutralise highly resistant viral agents such as hepatitis.</string>
    <string name="reading_first_paragraph_fifth">The overall effects of UV light treatment are variable,
        however, which leaves many municipal water treatment processes relying on chlorination. Its
        powerful and comprehensive antimicrobial effect not-withstanding, chlorination is also extremely
        inexpensive and remains the only antimicrobial treatment capable of ensuring water remains
        contaminant-free all the way through the pipes and to the taps of domestic homes. Many members
        of the public remain suspicious of water that has been treated with such a harsh chemical.
        Its ease of use and affordability has meant that chlorine often plays an important role in
        making tainted water supplies safe for consumption immediately after natural disasters have
        occurred.</string>
    <string name="reading_first_paragraph_sixth">Some water also undergoes distillation. This involves
        water being boiled until it converts to steam, which then passes through a cooling tube and
        becomes water again. Toxic compounds and impurities such as heavy metal residue are left
        behind in this process, so the steamed water is typically cleaner than the pre-distilled
        version. Unfortunately, distillation equipment also removes up to fourteen types of beneficial
        minerals that naturally occur in water. Consequently, those who rely on distilled water may
        need to take mineral supplements.</string>
    <string name="reading_first_paragraph_seventh">In developed countries, all forms of drinking water
        are typically subject to stringent quality control processes, so there is little evidence to
        suggest importing bottled water at significant expense will be safer or healthier than regular
        tap water from a municipal drinking supply. Both tap water and bottled water are tested for
        pathogens and contaminants and, aside from isolated cases related to issues such as faulty
        plumbing or old pipes, tap water is harmless. Nevertheless, many purchasers of bottled water
        still justify their choice on the quite reasonable basis that tap water has a distinctly
        unpleasant aftertaste related to the chlorination process it has undergone.</string>
    <string name="reading_first_paragraph_eight"> In Questions 1–5 \n
        Label the diagram below.</string>
    <string name="reading_second_warning">READING PASSAGE 2 \n
        You should spend about 20 minutes on Questions \n
        14–26, which are based on Reading Passage 2 below.</string>
    <string name="reading_second_title">THE INTERNATIONAL STYLE</string>
    <string name="reading_second_paragraph_first">A) In the early decades of the 20th century,
        many Western cities experienced a steep rise in demand for commercial and civic premises,
        due to population growth and expansion of the white-collar professions. At the same time,
        architects were growing discontented with the ornamental spirals and decorative features
        in the prevailing design ethos of art deco or art moderne. Once considered the height of
        sophistication, these styles were quickly becoming seen as pretentious and old-fashioned.
        In this confluence of movements, a new style of architecture emerged. It was simple,
        practical and strong; a new look for the modern city and the modern man. It was named
        ‘the international style’.</string>
    <string name="reading_second_paragraph_second">B) Although the international style first emerged
        in Western Europe in the 1920s, it found its fullest expression in American architecture and
        was given its name in a 1932 book of the same title. The first hints of it in America can be
        seen on the Empire State Building in New York City, which was completed in 1931. The top of
        the building, with its tapered crown, is decidedly art deco, yet the uniform shaft of the
        lower two thirds represents a pronounced step in a new direction. Later efforts, such as the
        United Nations Secretariat building (1952) and the Seagram Building (1954) came to exemplify the
        ‘true’ international style.</string>
    <string name="reading_second_paragraph_third">C) The architects of the international style broke
        with the past by rejecting virtually all non-essential ornamentation. They created blockish,
        flat-roofed skyscrapers using steel, stone and glass. A typical building facade in this style
        has an instantly recognisable ribbon design, characterised by strips of floor-to-ceiling
        windows separated by strips of metal panelling. Interiors showcased open spaces and fluid
        movements between separate areas of the building.</string>
    <string name="reading_second_paragraph_forth">D) Fans of the international style of modern
        buildings celebrated their sleek and economical contribution to modern cityscapes. While
        pre-modern architecture was typically designed to display the wealth and prestige of its
        landlords or occupants, the international style in some ways exhibited a more egalitarian
        tendency. As every building and every floor looked much the same, there was little attempt
        to use these designs to make a statement. This focus on function and practicality reflected
        a desire in mid-century Western cities to ‘get on with business’ and ‘give everyone a
        chance’, rather than lauding the dominant and influential institutions of the day through
        features such as Romanesque columns.</string>
    <string name="reading_second_paragraph_fifth">E) Detractors, however, condemned these buildings
        for showing little in the way of human spirit or creativity. For them, the international
        style represented not an ethos of equality and progress, but an obsession with profit and
        ‘the bottom line’ that removed spiritual and creative elements from public life and public
        buildings. Under the dominance of the international style, cities became places to work and
        do business, but not to express one’s desires or show individuality. It is perhaps telling
        that while banks and government departments favoured the international style, arts
        organisations rarely opted for its austerity.</string>
    <string name="reading_second_paragraph_sixth">F) By the mid-1970s, the international style was
        ubiquitous across key urban centres, dominating skylines to such an extent that many
        travellers complained they could get off a plane and not know where they were. By their
        nature, buildings in this style demanded very little of architects in the way of imagination,
        and a younger generation of designers was yearning to express their ideas and experiment
        in novel and unexpected ways. The outcome was a shift toward postmodernism, which celebrated
        much of what the international style had dismissed: decoration, style without function, and
        an overall sense of levity. By the turn of the 1980s, the international style was considered
        outdated and was falling rapidly out of favour.</string>
    <string name="reading_third_warning">READING PASSAGE 3 \n
        You should spend about 20 minutes on Questions \n
        27–40, which are based on Reading Passage 3 below.</string>
    <string name="reading_third_title">THE MPEMBA EFFECT</string>
    <string name="reading_third_paragraph_first">
        In 300 BC, the famous philosopher Aristotle wrote about a
        strange phenomenon that he had observed: “Many people, when they want to cool water quickly,
        begin by putting it in the sun.” Other philosophers over the ages noted the same result, but
        were unable to explain it. In 1963, a young Tanzanian student named Erasto Mpemba noticed that
        the ice cream he was making froze faster if the mix was placed in the freezer while warm than
        if it were at room temperature. He persisted in questioning why this occurred, and eventually
        physicist Denis Osborne began a serious investigation into what is now known as the Mpemba
        Effect. He and Mpemba co-authored a paper in New Scientist in 1969, which produced scientific
        descriptions of some of the many factors at work in freezing water.</string>
    <string name="reading_third_paragraph_second">
        It was initially hypothesised that the warm bowl melted itself a place in the
        ice on the freezer shelf, thus embedding its base in a ‘nest’ of ice, which would accelerate
        freezing. The hypothesis was tested by comparing the result when bowls of warm water were
        placed on ice and on a dry wire shelf; this demonstrated that the ice nest actually had
        little effect. A second suggestion was that the warmer water would be evaporating at its
        surface, thus reducing the volume needing to be frozen, but this idea was also shown to be
        insignificant. Thermometers placed in the water showed that the cooler water dropped to
        freezing temperature well before the warmer bowlful, and yet the latter always froze solid
        first. Experiments at different temperatures showed that water at 50C took longest to freeze
        in a conventional freezer, while water initially at 350C was quickest.</string>
    <string name="reading_third_paragraph_third">
        On further examination, an explanation for this paradox began to emerge. Losing
        heat from the water occurs at the points where it is in touch with the colder atmosphere of
        the freezer, namely the sides of the bowl and the water surface. A warm surface will lose heat
        faster than a cold one because of the contrast between the temperatures; but of course there
        is more heat to be lost from one bowl than the other! If the surface can be kept at a higher
        temperature, the higher rate of heat loss will continue. As long as the water remains liquid,
        the cooling portion on top will sink to the bottom of the bowl as the warmer water below rises
        to take its place. The early freezing that may occur on the sides and base of the container
        will amplify the effect.</string>
    <string name="reading_third_paragraph_forth">
        The bowl that is more uniformly cold will have far less temperature difference
        so the water flow will be minimal. Another inhibiting factor for this container is that ice
        will also form quite quickly on the surface. This not only acts as insulation, but will
        virtually stop the helpful effects of the water circulating inside the bowl. Ultimately, the
        rate of cooling the core of this body of water becomes so slow that the other warmer one is
        always fully frozen first. While there are limitations to this comparison (for example, we
        would not see such a result if one quantity were at 10C and another at 990C) this
        counter-intuitive result does hold true within the 5–350C range of temperatures indicated
        previously.</string>
    <string name="reading_third_paragraph_fifth">
        Since this paper was published, the validity of the research findings has been
        questioned by a number of reviewers. They point out that the initial experimental question was
        not clearly defined; for example, the researchers needed to decide on exactly what constituted
        freezing the water. They also state that the rate at which water freezes depends on a large
        number of variables.</string>
    <string name="reading_third_paragraph_sixth">
        Container size is one of these; for the Mpemba Effect to be noticed, the container
        must be large enough to allow a free circulation of water to take place, yet small enough for
        the freezing areas of the side and base to be effective at extracting heat too. Secondly,
        research at a University in St Louis, Missouri, suggests that the Mpemba Effect may be affected
        by water purity, or by dissolved gas in the water. Distilled water is totally free of the
        particles that are common in normal drinking water or mineral water. When suspended in water,
        these particles may have a small effect on the speed of cooling, especially as ice molecules
        tend to expel them into the surrounding water, where they become more concentrated. Just as
        salt dissolved in water will raise the boiling point and lower the temperature at which it
        freezes, the researchers found that the final portion of ordinary water needed extra cooling,
        below zero, before all was frozen solid.</string>
    <string name="reading_third_paragraph_seventh">
        One more factor that can distort the effect is observed if the bowls are not
        placed simultaneously into the same freezer. In this case, the freezer thermostat is more
        likely to register the presence of a hotter bowl than a colder one, and therefore the change
        in internal temperature causes a boost of freezing power as the motor is activated.</string>
    <string name="reading_third_paragraph_eight">
        The Mpemba Effect is still not fully understood, and researchers continue to
        delve into its underlying physics. Physicists cannot reach consensus. Some suggest that
        supercooling 1 is involved; others that the molecular bonds in the water molecules affect the
        rate of cooling and freezing of water. A 2013 competition to explain the phenomenon run by
        the Royal Society of Chemistry attracted more than 22,000 entries, with the winning one
        suggesting supercooling as an important factor so it seems the question and its underlying
        explanation continue to fascinate.</string>

    <!-- WritingActivity Texts -->
    <string name="writing_first_warning">WRITING TASK 1</string>
    <string name="writing_first_title">You should spend about 20 minutes on this task.The diagram
        below shows the stages and equipment used in the process of making matches. Summarize the
        information by selecting and reporting the main features, and make comparisons where
        relevant.</string>
    <string name="writing_first_text_first">Making matches</string>
    <string name="writing_second_warning">WRITING TASK 1</string>
    <string name="writing_second_title">MODEL RESPONSE</string>
    <string name="writing_second_text_first">The diagram shows that the process of manufacturing
        matches has several stages. The matchsticks are first cut, prepared, dried and moved to a
        storage area. After that, they are dipped into several chemicals and dried before being
        packaged.</string>
    <string name="writing_second_text_second">In the first phase, a log of wood is placed in a peeler
        and rotated, while a flat blade peels a long, thin sheet of wood, called veneer, from the outer
        surface of the log. The veneer proceeds to the chopper, which cuts it into small sticks.
        These are then soaked in a vat of ammonium phosphate. Afterwards, they are placed in a large,
        rotating drum. From there, the matches are dumped into a hopper and blown through a metal duct
        to the storage area.</string>
    <string name="writing_second_text_third">In the next stage, the sticks are moved from the storage
        area and they fall into a funnel-shaped device which lines them up to be inserted into holes
        on a long, continuous, perforated steel belt.As the belt moves along, the tips of the matches
        are dipped in a series of three tanks holding firstly paraffin wax, then base chemicals and
        finally tip chemicals. Next, the belt loops up and down through a drying area. In the final
        step of the process, the matches are packaged. \n \n 205 words.</string>


    <string name="writing_third_warning">MODEL RESPONSE FEEDBACK</string>
    <string name="writing_third_title">IELTS examiners rate the IELTS Writing Task 1 using 4 assessment
        criteria - Task Achievement, Coherence and Cohesion, Lexical Resource and Grammatical Range
        and Accuracy. Below you’ll find feedback on this sample model response.</string>
    <string name="writing_third_text_first">
        1. Task Achievement: What are the main stages of making matches? Is there a summary of these stages anywhere
        in the response? \n
        The first paragraph gives a general summary of the stages, which are then described in detail in the next two
        paragraphs.
    </string>
    <string name="writing_third_text_second">
        2. Coherence and Cohesion: Is the response easy to follow because of paragraphing and cohesive devices?
        There are three paragraphs here, the second two introduced by clear transitions: “In the first phase”, “In the next
        stage”. \n
        The paragraphs correspond to the main stages presented in the diagram and there are a variety of transitions
        within the paragraphs. “These” “Afterwards, they” “From there”, \n
        The response is easy to follow.
    </string>
    <string name="writing_third_text_third">
        3. Lexical Resource: Is there a variety of vocabulary, some from the prompt, but other vocabulary not from the
        prompt? Are words spelled correctly and used correctly?\n
        Words from the prompt are integrated well into the response and there are no spelling errors. Some words not
        from the prompt: “manufacturing”, “matchsticks”, “first phase”, “vat”.\n
        Vocabulary is used with precision and there is a wide range.
    </string>
    <string name="writing_third_text_forth">
        4. Grammatical Range and Accuracy: Are there a variety of sentence structures and are they accurate? Is
        punctuation accurate? “The matches are first cut”, “…proceeds to the chopper, which cuts it…”, “the sticks are moved…”\n
        There are a variety of sentence structures, and there are no errors. Punctuation is accurate.
    </string>

    <string name="writing_forth_warning">WRITING TASK 2</string>
    <string name="writing_forth_title">You should spend about 40 minutes on this task.</string>
    <string name="writing_forth_text_first">Write about the following topic:\n
        Lack of fresh water is becoming a global issue of increasing importance.\n
        What problems does this shortage cause?\n
        What measures could be taken to overcome these problems?\n
        Give reasons for your answer and include any relevant examples from your own knowledge or
        experience.\n Write at least 250 words.</string>
    <string name="writing_fifth_warning">WRITING TASK 2</string>
    <string name="writing_fifth_title">MODEL RESPONSE</string>
    <string name="writing_fifth_text_first">Water scarcity is becoming a significant global problem with far-reaching effects. Long-term solutions
require extensive government intervention in programmes, including research and climate mitigation
measures, but individuals also need to become aware of the need for water conservation. </string>
    <string name="writing_fifth_text_second">A major problem for all countries is the huge amount of water necessary for agriculture and industry.
When there is insufficient water, crops fail, animals die and people go hungry. Without an adequate
water supply, manufacturers, food producers, mining operations and businesses cannot succeed.
Ultimately, water is the key to economic prosperity. </string>
    <string name="writing_fifth_text_third">Water shortages create particular difficulties in developing countries. Firstly, many women and
children in these countries have to spend the whole day walking to and from a remote water source
to fetch water. Consequently, these children miss school and often do not receive an adequate
education. Secondly, the water that is available for daily use may be contaminated, and this can lead
to illness and even death. </string>
    <string name="writing_fifth_text_forth">One of the most important long-term solutions to this problem is to work towards reducing global
warming and climate change, as dry regions are becoming drier across the planet. Additionally,
pollution of waterways needs to be addressed, as we take steps to clean up our existing supplies of
this precious resource. Many old-fashioned irrigation schemes are generally very wasteful, so funds
need to be available for research into water conservation and new irrigation technologies. These
technologies could then be transferred to developing nations. At an individual level, we need to
become aware of wasteful water-use habits, such as watering lawns in the summer, or pouring our
grey water down the drain. In conclusion, the inadequate supply of fresh water is one of the most
crucial environmental problems facing our planet, and we need to work to preserve this precious
resource.\n 297 words </string>


    <string name="writing_sixth_warning">MODEL RESPONSE FEEDBACK</string>
    <string name="writing_sixth_title">IELTS examiners rate the IELTS Writing Task 1 using 4 assessment criteria - Task Response, Coherence
and Cohesion, Lexical Resource and Grammatical Range and Accuracy. Below you’ll find feedback on this
sample model response.</string>
    <string name="writing_sixth_text_first">1. Task Response: Are all parts of the prompt addressed, a position taken and supported and is the
response in an essay format?\n
All parts of the prompt are addressed and appropriate examples given. Problems described in the
second paragraph are related to economic prosperity in general, while in the third paragraph the
problems described are related more directly to developing countries.\n
Solutions are suggested in the third paragraph and a succinct conclusion is given at the end.
This is in an appropriate essay format.</string>
    <string name="writing_sixth_text_second">2. Coherence and Cohesion: Is the response easy to follow because of appropriate paragraphing, range
and accuracy of cohesive devices, and referencing?\n
There are five paragraphs here. The first serves as an introduction, the second, third, and fourth as
body paragraphs, and the last as a conclusion.\n
The introduction presents the idea of water scarcity, effects, and the idea of long-term solutions
requiring both government and individual action. Each body paragraph is well-organized and ideas
can easily be followed. The second paragraph begins, “A major problem”, then “When there is insufficient
water”, then “Without an adequate water supply”, then “Ultimately…”\n
The fourth paragraph, which covers solutions is easy to follow. “One of the most important …”,\n
“Additionally”, “as we take steps…”, “These technologies could then…”, “At an individual level…”\n
Both overall organization of paragraphs and internal organization is clear and a range of discourse
markers is used accurately. </string>
    <string name="writing_sixth_text_third">3. Lexical Resource: How wide a range of vocabulary is used and how accurate is usage and spelling?
There is a wide range of vocabulary here with no error. Less common items are used quite skillfully.\n
Examples: “Water scarcity”, “far-reaching effects”, “extensive government intervention”, “climate mitigation”. </string>
    <string name="writing_sixth_text_forth">4. Grammatical Range and Accuracy: How wide is the range of grammatical structures and how frequent
are errors? Is punctuation accurate?\n
There is a wide range of grammatical structures here with no error. Punctuation is accurate.\n
Examples: “Long-term solutions require extensive government intervention in programmes, including
research and climate mitigation measures, but individuals also need to become aware of the need for water
conservation.”, “…spend the whole day walking to and from a remote water source to fetch water.”, “…the water
that is available for daily use may be contaminated, and this can lead to illness and even death.” </string>

    <!-- SpeakingActivity Texts -->
    <string name="speaking_first_warning">Speaking \n 11–14 Minutes </string>
    <string name="speaking_first_title">PART 1 – INTRODUCTION AND INTERVIEW: \n Let’s talk about
        your home town or village. </string>
    <string name="speaking_first_text_first">What kind of place is it? \n
        • What’s the most interesting part of your town/village? \n
        • What kind of jobs do the people in your town/village do? \n
        • Would you say it’s a good place to live? Why? </string>

    <string name="speaking_second_warning">Speaking \n
        11-14 Minutes \n
        PART 2 – INDIVIDUAL LONG TURN: </string>
    <string name="speaking_second_title">Candidate Task Card \n
        Describe a well-known person you like or admire. \n
        You should say: \n
        • Who is this person?  \n
        • What has this person done?  \n
        • Why is this person well-known? \n
        • Explain why you like or admire\n this person? </string>
    <string name="speaking_second_text_first">
        • You will have to talk about the topic for 1 to 2 minutes.\n
        • You have one minute to think about what you’re going to say.\n
        • You can make some notes to help you if you wish.</string>
    <string name="speaking_third_warning">We’ve been talking about a well-known person that you
        admire and I’d like to discuss with you a few more questions related to this topic. Let’s
        consider famous people in your country.</string>
    <string name="speaking_third_title">
        • What kind of people become famous in your country?\n
        • What’s different about people who became famous in the past with the people who become
    famous these days?\n
        • Do you think it was more difficult to become famous in the past?\n
        • What kind people may become famous in the future?\n </string>

</resources>